Axel Foley is back. Back where he doesn't belong.
Beverly Hills Cop II is a action, comedy, crime film directed by Tony Scott.
Axel Foley returns to the land of sunshine and palm trees to investigate
the near-fatal shooting of police Captain Andrew Bogomil.
With the help of Sgt.
Taggart and Det.
Rosewood, they soon uncover that the shooting is associated with a series of "alphabet"
robberies masterminded by a heartless weapons kingpin—and the chase is on.
Axel Foley, played by Eddie Murphy.
Billy Rosewood, played by Judge Reinhold.
John Taggart, played by John Ashton.
Maxwell Dent, played by Jürgen Prochnow.
Andrew Bogomil, played by Ronny Cox.
Karla Fry, played by Brigitte Nielsen.
Beverly Hills Cop II is a 1987 American buddy cop action comedy film directed by Tony
Scott, written by Larry Ferguson and Warren Skaaren, and starring Eddie Murphy.
It is the sequel to the 1984 film Beverly Hills Cop and the second
installment in the Beverly Hills Cop film series.
Murphy returns as Detroit police detective Axel Foley, who reunites with Beverly Hills detectives Billy Rosewood (Judge Reinhold) and John
Taggart (John Ashton) to stop a criminal organization after Captain Andrew Bogomil (Ronny Cox) is shot and seriously wounded.
The film was released on May 20, 1987, by Paramount Pictures.
It received mixed reviews from critics on release, but it was a box
office success, grossing $300 million worldwide.
Additionally, the film was nominated for an Oscar, as well as a Golden Globe
Award for Best Original Song, for Bob Seger's "Shakedown".
Two sequels, Beverly Hills Cop III and Beverly Hills Cop:
Axel F, were released in 1994 and 2024.
The film explores themes of police, arms smuggling,
intensive care, undercover, detective.
The tone is lighthearted.